

Diego Moisés Llano Moraga

+56967095602

diegolgo@gmail.com

Statistical Engineering

11 years of experience

Professional with extensive grade of experience in areas of data analysis, work in technical and operational areas, extensive development in surveying and process modelers, improvements, and design, analysis and management tools in different languages and platforms. High capacity, work under pressure and adaptability. Strength in learning software.

Experience

Nacional Institute of Statistics, INE Chile, Government

Operations coordinator

2017 - 2021

Coordinator of the Quarterly Construction Survey, involve in the creation and production of the quarterly income index for large companies, published and currently used. Previously, I was an economic analyst for the project, conducting business research, analysis of time series, I develop an analysis tool (currently in use), and development of management tools. creation of homogeneous layers for limits of confidence, presentation of good analysis practices to the rest of the institution, creation of SQL data interconnection tools to improve database analysis, validation, survey and process design, etc.

Technical Coordinator

2014 - 2015

Subrogation leadership, Analysis and review of data base, Innovation projects and R&D Expenditure of National Company's (2 National Surveys). Index of spending on research and development in Chile are published, as well as spending on innovation, for which work was carried out on data validation, improvements of BD, analysis processes, Operational Coordination, hiring of personnel and training, planning and programming.

Economics Analyst

2013 - 2013

Inventory's Survey: I participated in the first publication of the inventory index in Chile, creation and standardize processes (flowcharts, documentation and modeling), data analysis, and estimations of limits for economics rate index, time series, among others, training to the rest of the analysts and participating in the whole process.

Tecnyca Chile (Pharmaceutical Industry)

Validation Engineering

2012 - 2013

Hired to works as mathematician to support experimental designs in pharmaceutical manufacturing. Evaluation of current analysis processes. Preparation, validation and execution of protocols for the qualification of pharmaceutical manufacturing equipment. Work on FDA report 40, and ICH reports on good drug manufacturing practices. Risk Analysis, and Field Validations in different laboratories throughout Chile. (Golden Omega, Laboratory Chile, Saval, and others).

Woodtech MS / Technology (Cellulose Industry)

Process data Chief, Statistical Engineering

2010 - 2011

Hired as a Statistical Analyst in the Products and development area (I&D), to evaluate the statistical modeling process, generate modifications and establish development policies, to later move to the Operations area, where I took on jobs as Process Manager, where support is provided for the products, among the tasks stand out; calibrations, data analysis, model maintenance, automation, sampling. Direct visits of personal supervision and review in the execution of sampling processes in the field of different cellulose plants in Chile and Brazil.

Viollier & Associates, Insurances

Statistic Data Analyst

2010 - 2010

Mortgage portfolio statistician, analyst, insurance settlement. I was in charge of the mortgage portfolio team, being my main responsibility the maintenance and analysis of the claims database, reports to companies and clients, Superintendency Reports, Supervision of regional portfolios.

Education

Statistical Engineering, plus bachelor's degree,

University of Playa Ancha, graduation 2009

5 years of active participation on Nacional Congress of Statistic (Chile), and 2008 exhibitor about Ruin Theory (loss reserve modeling).

Technical administration

Commercial institute (Technical high school), graduation 2001 Legal company creations.

Skills highlights, and certifications

Data analysis STATA / Kibernum

- Access advance / UNAB
- Leadership skills / Segic USACH
- Technical English for statistics / UDLA
- programming on R / PUC
- SPSS advance / INE
- Skills to make effective presentations / Segic USACH
- training and preparation of courses / Segic USACH
- Microdata and standard metadata documentation workshop DDI / INE

Software:

• Stata, Office- Power Bi, SPSS, Statistics, Minitab, R, Sql, Python, Access, Linux, bash

Languages

• English - Spanish

spanish web version: https://diegolgo.github.io/curriculum/